<para version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <section>
        <title>tuple space</title>
        <para>A tuple space is an implementation of the associative memory paradigm for parallel/distributed computing.
            It provides a repository of tuples that can be accessed concurrently. As an illustrative example, consider
            that there are a group of processors that produce pieces of data and a group of processors that use the
            data. Producers post their data as tuples in the space, and the consumers then retrieve data from the space
            that match a certain pattern. This is also known as the blackboard metaphor. Tuple space may be thought as a
            form of distributed shared memory. Tuple spaces were the theoretical underpinning of the Linda language
            developed by David Gelernter and Nicholas Carriero at Yale University.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>object space</title>
        <para>Object Spaces is a paradigm for development of distributed computing applications. It is characterized by
            the existence of logical entities, called Object Spaces. All the participants of the distributed application
            share an Object Space. A provider of a service encapsulates the service as an Object, and puts it in the
            Object Space. Clients of a service then access the Object Space, find out which object provides the needed
            service, and have the request serviced by the object. Object Spaces, as a computing paradigm, was put
            forward by David Gelernter at Yale University. Gelernter developed a language called Linda to support the
            concept of global object coordination. Object Space can be thought of as a virtual repository, shared
            amongst providers and accessors of network services, which are themselves abstracted as objects. Processes
            communicate among each other using these shared objects — by updating the state of the objects as and when
            needed. An object, when deposited into a space, needs to be registered with an Object Directory in the
            Object Space. Any processes can then identify the object from the Object Directory, using properties lookup,
            where the property specifying the criteria for the lookup of the object is its name or some other property
            which uniquely identifies it. A process may choose to wait for an object to be placed in the Object Space,
            if the needed object is not already present. Objects, when deposited in an Object Space are passive, i.e.,
            their methods cannot be invoked while the objects are in the Object Space. Instead, the accessing process
            must retrieve it from the Object Space into its local memory, use the service provided by the object, update
            the state of the object and place it back into the Object Space.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>java space</title>
        <para>JavaSpaces is a service specification providing a distributed object exchange and coordination mechanism
            (which may or may not be persistent) for Java objects. It is used to store the distributed system state and
            implement distributed algorithms. In a JavaSpace, all communication partners (peers) communicate and
            coordinate by sharing state. JavaSpaces can be used to achieve scalability through parallel processing, it
            can also be used to provide reliable storage of objects through distributed replication, although this won't
            survive a total power failure like a disk; it is regarded by many to be reliable as long as the power is
            reliable. Distribution can also be to remote locations; however, this is rare as JavaSpaces are usually used
            to low-latency, high performance applications rather than reliable object caching. The most common software
            pattern used in JavaSpaces is the Master-Worker pattern. The Master hands out units of work to the "space",
            and these are read, processed and written back to the space by the workers. In a typical environment there
            are several "spaces", several masters and many workers; the workers are usually designed to be generic, i.e.
            they can take any unit of work from the space and process the task.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>elsecloud's space evolution</title>
        <para>During development and evaluation of other Java Space implementation we realized that something needs to
            be changed in object space principles (and something needs to be extended) to match with modern
            architectures and exchange patterns. As result of such evaluation first of all elsecloud is not just object
            space, but in fact it is transactional in-memory object storage(with proper row level concurrent data access
            protection) and support of Read Committed transaction isolation level plus some steroids (like exclusive
            read lock, not just exclusive write lock on row level which can). In fact SQL/NOSQL databases and space
            based storages are very similar in terminology, but very different in access patterns and performance. It is
            also important to realize that elsecloud is not replacement for databases, quite the contrary we designed
            the system for tight integration with external data storages(like RDBMS) in terms of initial data load,
            durable data persistency. The goal is not to be the master(golden source) of data, but rather adopt
            application to use jspace as highly concurrent, ultra fast data manipulation engine (capable to persist
            changes back to the database in synchronous or asynchronous manner) during application's lifecycle.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>java space API basics</title>
        <para>
            JavaSpace API is extremely lightweight and powerful. There are only 3 basic methods for data manipulation:
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <literal>write</literal>
                        - save (or update) entry in space
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <literal>fetch</literal>
                        - read (and optionally remove) entry from the space
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <literal>notify</literal>
                        - notify space clients about changes in space (insert/update/delete)
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <note>
                <para>
                    elsecloud API is a little different from original Java Spaces API and the main difference is that
                    there are no dedicated
                    <literal>take/read</literal>
                    methods, instead there is simple
                    <literal>fetch</literal>
                    operation. Don't worry because of such low-level API, this is just core methods and technically you
                    wouldn't use them directly. In most cases SimplisticJSpace proxy interface is something you are
                    looking for - you will get sugar methods like
                    <literal>take,read,takeById,readById,evict,evictById.</literal>
                </para>
                <para>
                    Conversion:
                    <emphasis role="bold">read/take</emphasis>
                    is in fact just
                    <emphasis role="bold">fetch</emphasis>
                    operation (in terms of low-level API), but we will use read/take logical names further.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                The combination of given 3 methods is really dark power.
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <literal>write+read</literal>
                            perfectly matches with network distributed/data caching oriented solutions.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <literal>write+take</literal>
                        is perfect for massive data processing systems with network decoupled data producers and data
                        processing nodes (working fully asynchronously on top of map-reduce parallel processing
                        pattern).
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <literal>write+take+notify</literal>
                        great for messaging systems. Application code can be notified with space changes
                        asynchronously(like JMS). Another great example for notify is so-called 'local cache' -
                        something cached on remote client's side(in order to reduce network trips) and something that
                        gets updated automatically in case of data changes on remote server node.
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <note>
                <title>Template Matching</title>
                <para>Internally space entities are stored in form of off-heap byte array and jspace capable to
                    de-serialized this blob to array of property values very efficiently. Data retrieval is done using
                    so-called template matching mechanism(something similar to hibernate's findByExample method). You
                    would need to create template object, set filter properties(only those properties you are interested
                    in) and leave not needed fields with blank(null) value. jspace will take care and match template
                    with de-serialized property values for each entity.</para>
                <para>Also it is very important to understand that elsecloud capable to do lookup by id extremely fast.
                    Also we have a concept of space indexes(this allows to get near id-based lookup performance for
                    non-id pattern matching).</para>
            </note>
        </para>
    </section>
</para>